<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Eugenie Dugoua</title>
    <link>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Eugenie Dugoua</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Your Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Satellite Data for the Social Sciences: Measuring Rural Electrification with Nighttime Luminosity.</title>
      <link>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.etal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.etal2018/</guid>
      <description>Remote sensing data has the potential to revolutionize social science. One of the most prominent examples of this is the Nighttime Lights dataset, which provides digital measures of nighttime luminosity from 1992 to 2013. This study evaluates the Nighttime Lights data against detailed rural electrification data from the 2011 Census of India. The results suggest that many nighttime luminosity measures derived from satellite data are surprisingly accurate for measuring rural electrification, even at the village level and using simple statistical tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic and socio-economic barriers to rural electrification: New evidence from Indian villages.</title>
      <link>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.etal2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.etal2017/</guid>
      <description>The International Energy Agency estimates that more than a billion people remain without household electricity access. However, countries such as India have recently made major progress in rural electrification. Who has benefited from these achievements? We focus on 714 villages in six energy-poor states of northern and eastern India to investigate trends in electricity access. We use data both from the 2011 Census of India and an original energy access survey conducted in 2014 and 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relative Deprivation and Energy Poverty: When Does Unequal Access to Electricity Cause Dissatisfaction?</title>
      <link>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.urpelainen2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eugeniedugoua.github.io/publication/dugoua.urpelainen2014/</guid>
      <description>In the least developed countries, unequal access to infrastructure is a major form of inequality. We examine the conditions under which unequal electricity access causes dissatisfaction. The question is important because grievances could prompt demands for policy change. We argue that feelings of relative deprivation both cause dissatisfaction and create hope for improvement. Empirically, we analyze household survey data from five East African countries. All else constant, households living close to a power line are less satisfied with their lighting solution but also have more hope for improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>